=Within The Grip=
=그립 내부=
=Episode 6=
=에피소드 6=
(Even a Rabbit Bites)
(토끼한테 물려도)
Dear.
에게.
Step aside!
물러서세요!
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
What am I doing?
내가 뭘 하고 있는 거지?
An assassin appeared in the mansion. I'm here for Zhaoxi's safety.
저택에 암살자가 나타났습니다. 나는 Zhaoxi의 안전을 위해 여기에 있습니다.
But you're blocking me.
그런데 당신이 나를 막고 있어요.
- Could there be...? - There's no assassin.
- 혹시...? - 암살자는 없어요.
Instead, someone wants to use the opportunity to settle personal scores.
대신 누군가가 사용하고 싶어합니다. 개인 점수를 정할 수 있는 기회.
How dare you!
감히!
Is this how your master taught you to slander others?
주인님은 이런가요? 남을 비방하는 법을 가르쳤습니까?
You claim there's no assassin in this courtyard.
당신은 암살자가 없다고 주장해요 이 안뜰에.
Then what is this?
그럼 이건 뭐죠?
Seize her.
그녀를 붙잡으세요.
(Vast Mind, Eternal Will) An assassin broke in tonight.
(광활한 마음, 영원한 의지) 오늘 밤에 암살자가 침입했습니다.
Zhaoxi, for your safety, please cooperate with the search.
자오시님, 당신의 안전을 위해 수색에 협조해 주십시오.
Zhaoxi.
자오시.
Sorry.
죄송합니다.
Chaosheng, why are you pressing me so hard?
차오성아, 왜 그래? 나를 그렇게 세게 누르나요?
Just because I never compete, you think you can push me around?
나는 결코 경쟁하지 않기 때문에 네가 날 밀어낼 수 있을 것 같아?
No.
아니요.
If it's about safety,
안전에 관한 것이라면
where were you when bandits attacked me?
도적들이 나를 공격했을 때 당신은 어디에 있었나요?
Yes. You didn't search for me. You just set up a memorial hall at home.
예. 당신은 나를 검색하지 않았습니다. 집에 기념관을 차렸을 뿐입니다.
Such brotherhood.
그런 형제애.
How am I supposed to repay you?
내가 어떻게 갚아야 하지?
Alright, it's just hearsay.
알았어, 그냥 소문일 뿐이야.
I was sleeping with my wife just now.
나는 지금 아내와 자고 있었습니다.
You know full well I'm injured.
내가 다친 걸 당신도 잘 알잖아요.
Yet you barged into my room at this hour with such an excuse.
그런데 당신이 내 방에 들이닥쳤어요 이 시간에 그런 핑계로.
What exactly do you want?
정확히 무엇을 원하시나요?
Chaosheng.
조성.
I won't see you out.
나는 당신을 보지 않을 것입니다.
Why did you...?
왜 그랬어...?
You didn't need to do that just now.
지금 당장은 그렇게 할 필요가 없었습니다.
You could have just made up an excuse to send him away.
방금 화해했을 수도 있었잖아 그를 보내기 위한 핑계.
Let me apply the medicine.
약을 바르도록 할게요.
You shouldn't have confronted him.
당신은 그 사람과 맞서지 말았어야 했어요.
Zhaoxi has a gentle nature.
Zhaoxi는 온화한 성격을 가지고 있습니다.
He doesn't argue with others.
그는 다른 사람들과 논쟁하지 않습니다.
Luckily,
다행히
he didn't suspect anything.
그는 아무것도 의심하지 않았습니다.
What else could I do? Even a rabbit bites.
내가 또 무엇을 할 수 있나요? 토끼에게도 물립니다.
A man, no matter how gentle his nature,
남자는 성격이 아무리 온순해도
should protect his own wife.
자기 아내를 보호해야 한다.
So this is how your beloved husband
사랑하는 남편이 이렇게 됐군요
protects you?
당신을 보호합니까?
It's late. Get some sleep.
늦었어. 잠을 좀 자세요.
Stay here tonight. I'm afraid they might come back.
오늘 밤은 여기 있어. 그들이 다시 돌아올까봐 두렵습니다.
(Earth)
(지구)
Master.
주인.
I think you know why I summoned you.
내가 왜 당신을 불렀는지 알 것 같아요.
Yes.
예.
These past two years, I've had you by Chaosheng's side.
지난 2년 동안, 나는 당신을 Chaosheng의 곁에 두었습니다.
(Zhe Zhu, Earth Unit, Xuanji Pavilion) You remember
(Zhe Zhu, 지구 유닛, Xuanji Pavilion) 기억나지
how to do a task, right?
작업을 수행하는 방법, 그렇죠?
Yes.
예.
(Earth)
(지구)
Here is the task and your identity.
여기에 임무와 귀하의 신원이 있습니다.
It's only an Earth-level task, but it has wide-reaching implications.
그것은 단지 지구 수준의 임무일 뿐이고, 그러나 그것은 광범위한 의미를 가지고 있습니다.
Your painting skills are among the best in the Earth Unit.
당신의 그림 실력 지구 단위에서 최고 중 하나입니다.
So you'll complete this task.
따라서 이 작업을 완료하게 됩니다.
I will not fail the task.
나는 그 일을 실패하지 않을 것이다.
Go.
가다.
(Tianfeng Pavilion, Gu Mansion)
(Tianfeng Pavilion, Gu Mansion)
Who does he think he is?
그는 자신이 누구라고 생각합니까?
Showing me such disrespect!
나한테 이런 무례함을 보여주다니!
Without his mother,
그의 어머니가 없었다면,
Father wouldn't give such an absurd order!
아버지는 안 주시겠다고 정말 터무니없는 명령이군요!
Where is Zhe Zhu?
Zhe Zhu는 어디에 있나요?
Miss Zhe Zhu went to the back mountain.
Zhe Zhu 선생님은 뒷산으로 가셨습니다.
There's likely a new task for her.
그녀에게는 새로운 임무가 있을 것 같습니다.
Master.
주인.
You may leave.
떠날 수도 있습니다.
Yes.
예.
There's a new task?
새로운 임무가 있나요?
The Pavilion Master ordered me to pack and depart tomorrow.
파빌리온 마스터가 나에게 명령했다 짐을 싸서 내일 출발하려고요.
Although this task may be dangerous,
이 작업은 위험할 수 있지만
the reward will be huge.
보상은 엄청날 것이다.
Then I'll be of great help to you.
그러면 제가 당신에게 큰 도움이 될 것입니다.
It's dangerous?
위험해요?
Don't worry, Master. I will complete the task successfully.
걱정하지 마세요, 선생님. 나는 그 임무를 성공적으로 완수할 것이다.
Let me see.
어디 보자.
It's just the two of us here. Relax.
여기는 우리 둘뿐이에요. 안심하다.
No one else will know.
다른 사람은 아무도 알 수 없습니다.
Master, this task is from the Xuanji Pavilion...
선생님, 이번 임무는 Xuanji Pavilion에서 왔습니다...
Who is your real master?
당신의 진짜 주인은 누구입니까?
I haven't forgotten.
나는 잊지 않았다.
Ever since I became your death guard,
내가 너의 죽음의 경비병이 된 이후로,
my life has belonged to you.
내 인생은 당신의 것입니다.
My accepting this task from the Xuanji Pavilion
나는 이 임무를 수락한다 Xuanji Pavilion에서
is also in hopes of better assisting you in the future.
또한 희망하고있다 앞으로는 더 잘 도와드리겠습니다.
If that's the case,
그렇다면
give it to me.
나에게 줘.
(Prince Consort seeks painters.)
(Prince Consort는 화가를 찾고 있습니다.)
(Blindness for those who fail. Investigate.)
(그들의 실명 실패하는 사람. 조사하세요.)
I remember in the Xuanji Pavilion,
나는 Xuanji Pavilion에서
the only first-class painters are you and Yuluo.
유일한 일류 화가들 너랑 Yuluo야?
Yes.
예.
Go tell them you can't take this task.
가서 이 일을 맡을 수 없다고 말하세요.
But... Master.
그런데... 선생님.
You know this task is dangerous.
이 작업이 위험하다는 것을 알고 있습니다.
How could I let you risk your life?
어떻게 당신이 목숨을 걸게 놔둘 수 있겠습니까?
I don't need
필요하지 않아
to teach you what to do, do I?
당신에게 무엇을 해야 할지 가르쳐 주려고요, 그렇죠?
You're awake.
당신은 깨어있습니다.
Seems I came at a bad time. I'll wait in the courtyard.
제가 나쁜 시기에 온 것 같습니다. 나는 안뜰에서 기다릴 것이다.
No rush.
서두르지 마세요.
Are you just using me and then throwing me away?
너 나만 이용하고 있는 거야? 그러다가 나를 버리면?
Who said I'd throw you away?
내가 널 버리겠다고 누가 그랬어?
Honey, what more do you want?
여보, 뭘 더 원해요?
Is this enough?
이 정도면 충분합니까?
(Fufeng Pavilion)
(푸펑 파빌리온)
You came so soon.
너무 빨리 오셨어요.
Take your time.
천천히 시간을 가지세요.
I'm not in a hurry.
나는 서두르지 않습니다.
Didn't we agree days ago to take your and Zhaoxi's measurements?
우리 며칠 전에 합의하지 않았나요? 당신과 Zhaoxi의 치수를 재려고요?
So I've brought them with me.
그래서 나는 그것들을 가지고 왔습니다.
Go ahead.
계속하세요.
Yes.
예.
Wanniang, this is the lady needing measurements today.
완낭, 이 사람이 바로 그 여자야 오늘 측정이 필요해.
So you're Leng Yan's...
그럼 당신은 Leng Yan의 사람이군요...
Yes. Though I often stayed by Leng Yan's side,
예. 자주 묵었지만 Leng Yan 옆에서
I knew little of his business.
나는 그의 사업에 대해 거의 알지 못했습니다.
But half a month before his death,
하지만 그가 죽기 반 달 전,
a man in black did come to hire him.
검은 옷을 입은 남자가 그를 고용하러 왔습니다.
Who's there?
거기 누구 있어요?
(About ten days ago,)
(약 10일 전,)
(he left some silver at night as a deposit.)
(그는 약간의 은을 남겼다 밤에는 보증금으로 제공됩니다.)
I think I heard him say...
그 사람이 말하는 걸 들은 것 같은데...
Outside the city at Hai hour.
하이 시간에 도시 외곽.
You'll get the rest when the job's done.
작업이 완료되면 나머지를 얻을 수 있습니다.
Alright.
괜찮은.
(At Hai hour.)
(하이 시간에.)
(And outside the city?)
(그리고 도시 밖에서?)
I noticed a faint, unique fragrance.
나는 희미하고 독특한 향기를 발견했습니다.
It wasn't any common scent.
흔한 향은 아니었어요.
Likely custom-blended for nobility.
귀족을 위해 맞춤 제작되었을 가능성이 높습니다.
As a perfume connoisseur, I remember it clearly.
향수 전문가로서, 나는 그것을 분명히 기억한다.
Later, when Miss Gu had me listen to Master Chaosheng's voice,
나중에 구씨가 나를 낳았을 때 조성 선생님의 목소리를 들어보세요,
(I realized his scent matched that night's exactly.)
(그 사람의 향기를 알아차렸어 그날 밤과 정확히 일치합니다.)
Chaosheng made his fragrance specially.
Chaosheng은 특별히 향수를 만들었습니다.
He's the only user.
그는 유일한 사용자입니다.
Many in the mansion know this. You can verify it, Yuluo.
저택의 많은 사람들이 이것을 알고 있습니다. 확인해볼 수 있어요, 율루오.
Chaosheng is involved in Zhaoxi's incident.
Chaosheng이 참여했습니다. Zhaoxi 사건에서.
I just wonder how Father will punish him.
난 그냥 궁금해 아버지가 그를 어떻게 처벌하실지.
At Hai hour?
하이 아워에?
Did Leng Yan ever act ahead of schedule?
Leng Yan이 일정보다 앞서 행동한 적이 있나요?
Moving early risked complications.
조기에 이사하면 합병증이 발생할 수 있습니다.
He never changed clients' set times.
그는 고객이 정한 시간을 결코 바꾸지 않았습니다.
He called it an unbreakable rule.
그는 그것을 깨뜨릴 수 없는 법칙이라고 불렀습니다.
Did Leng Yan mention anything when he returned?
Leng Yan이 언급했나요? 그가 돌아왔을 때 아무것도 없었나요?
I never participated in his business.
나는 그의 사업에 참여한 적이 없습니다.
Nor did I ask.
나도 묻지 않았다.
But I remember he returned very late that day.
하지만 나는 기억한다 그는 그날 매우 늦게 돌아왔습니다.
He was muttering angrily,
그는 화가 나서 중얼거렸다.
"I can't get my pay now."
"지금은 월급을 받을 수 없어요."
His task failed, didn't it?
그의 임무는 실패했지, 그렇지?
Didn't Master Zhaoxi return safely?
조시선생은 무사히 돌아오지 않았나요?
Was he injured?
부상을 입었나요?
No.
아니요.
The deposit silver from that day.
그날부터 입금된 은은입니다.
Was it taken away when Leng Yan was killed?
빼앗긴 걸까 Leng Yan이 죽었을 때?
No.
아니요.
But when I fetched my clothes later,
하지만 나중에 옷을 가져왔을 때
I found another bag of silver hidden behind the door.
또 다른 은가방을 찾았어요 문 뒤에 숨겨져 있습니다.
There must be someone else behind Zhaoxi's assassination.
분명 다른 사람도 있을 텐데 자오시 암살의 배후.
Since Zhaoxi doesn't know martial arts, the killer returning unhurt is possible.
조희는 무술을 모르기 때문에 살인자가 무사히 돌아올 수도 있다.
Guards said the assassination happened at Xu hour.
경비병들은 암살이 있었다고 말했다 Xu 시간에 일어났습니다.
If true,
사실이라면
when Leng Yan arrived, Zhaoxi might've already been...
Leng Yan이 도착했을 때, Zhaoxi는 이미...
Besides, if Chaosheng hired and then killed the killer,
게다가 조성에게 고용된다면 살인자를 죽인 다음
he'd take away the silver to clear suspicion.
그 사람은 은화를 빼앗아 갈 거야 의심을 없애기 위해.
But he secretly delivered the second payment.
그런데 그 사람이 몰래 배달을 하더군요. 두 번째 결제.
Meaning he likely didn't know Leng Yan failed.
그 사람이 그럴 가능성이 있다는 뜻이야 Leng Yan이 실패한 것을 몰랐습니다.
The Xu hour.
쑤 시간.
Interesting. So...
흥미로운. 그럼...
Chaosheng hired the killer, but someone struck first.
Chaosheng은 살인자를 고용했습니다. 그런데 누군가 먼저 쳤다.
He was unaware of that.
그는 그것을 모르고 있었습니다.
Then who appeared at Xu hour that day?
그렇다면 그날 쉬시간에는 누가 나타났는가?
Or perhaps Chaosheng staged this whole play.
아니면 Chaosheng일 수도 있습니다. 이 연극 전체를 상연했습니다.
What do you think?
어떻게 생각하나요?
Maybe it was me.
어쩌면 나였을 수도 있습니다.
How will you handle this, Yuluo?
이 일을 어떻게 처리할 건가요, 율루오?
Since Zhaoxi returned safely,
조희가 무사히 돌아왔으니
this is just a family matter.
이건 단지 가족 문제일 뿐이에요.
We're doing your wedding gown fitting today.
우리는하고있다 오늘 당신의 웨딩드레스 피팅.
Wanniang.
완낭.
Don't worry.
괜찮아요.
No rush.
서두르지 마세요.
I appreciate
감사합니다
your kindness.
당신의 친절함.
But I'm more curious about how you two met
그런데 그게 더 궁금하네요 너희 둘이 어떻게 만났는지에 대해
and how you learned the details.
자세한 내용을 어떻게 배웠는지.
How have you been lately, Master?
선생님, 최근 잘 지내셨나요?
Did they notice anything?
그들은 뭔가를 알아차렸나요?
I wanted to go to you at the last lantern event.
너에게 가고 싶었어 마지막 랜턴 이벤트에서.
But that female guard kept shadowing you.
그런데 그 여자 경비병이 계속 당신을 따라다녔어요.
Are you sure
확실해요
Gu Zhaoxi has no martial arts skills?
구자오시는 무술 실력이 없나요?
Yes. He's been frail since childhood and couldn't practice martial arts.
예. 그는 어릴 때부터 몸이 약했다 그리고 무술을 연습할 수도 없었습니다.
Why do you ask?
왜 물어보나요?
If that's true,
그것이 사실이라면,
why did Gu Chaosheng test my martial skills?
구차오셩은 왜 그랬나? 내 무술 실력을 시험해볼까?
It seems those two aren't allies.
그 둘은 동맹이 아닌 것 같습니다.
(Gu Chaosheng hired assassin Leng Yan to kill Gu Zhaoxi.)
(구조성 고용 암살자 Leng Yan이 Gu Zhaoxi를 죽입니다.)
Leng Yan.
렝옌.
Yes.
예.
Gu Chaosheng is truly ruthless.
Gu Chaosheng은 정말 무자비합니다.
He hired an assassin to kill his own brother.
그는 암살자를 고용했다 자기 동생을 죽이려고.
So Gu Zhaoxi was truly murdered by him?
그럼 구자오시는 정말로 그 사람에 의해 살해된 걸까요?
And the one you encountered was also...?
그리고 당신이 만난 사람도...?
Turns out
알고보니
blood isn't thicker
피는 더 진하지 않아
than money and power.
돈과 권력보다
Master.
주인.
It's not as simple as it looks.
보이는 것만큼 간단하지 않습니다.
Return to the palace and investigate
궁전으로 돌아가서 조사해 보세요
what that person has been doing lately.
그 사람 최근에 뭐하고 있었는지.
Yes.
예.
Gu Yuluo has a blade wound on her back, likely from the past month.
구위뤄는 등에 칼날 상처가 있고, 아마 지난달부터였을 거예요.
Investigate it carefully.
주의 깊게 조사하십시오.
Yes.
예.
Master, do you suspect it was her?
선생님, 그 사람이 그 사람일 거라고 생각하시나요?
Dear.
에게.
♪Willows sway in the twilight breeze♪
♪버드나무가 황혼의 미풍에 흔들리네요♪
♪Ancient alleys guard time's secrets♪
♪고대 골목은 시간의 비밀을 지킨다♪
♪Bluestones bear life's imprints♪
♪블루스톤에는 생명의 흔적이 새겨져 있습니다♪
♪Falling petals, endless longing♪
♪떨어지는 꽃잎, 끝없는 그리움♪
♪Longing lingers within my heart♪
♪그리움은 내 마음속에 남아있습니다♪
♪Zither strings sigh for the sorrow parting♪
♪치터 현의 한숨 슬픈 이별을 위해♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪과거 이야기가 내 영혼에 둥지를 틀고 있습니다♪
♪Affection lingers, unforgettable♪
♪애정은 잊혀지지 않습니다♪
♪Ink-stained scrolls recall bygones♪
♪잉크 묻은 두루마리는 과거를 회상합니다♪
♪Each stroke holds a thought♪
♪획 하나하나에 생각이 담겨있습니다♪
♪Prosperity fades like dreams♪
♪번영은 꿈처럼 사라져 버립니다♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪과거 이야기가 내 영혼에 둥지를 틀고 있습니다♪
♪Affection lingers, unforgettable♪
♪애정은 잊혀지지 않습니다♪
♪Ink-stained scrolls recall bygones♪
♪잉크 묻은 두루마리는 과거를 회상합니다♪
♪Each stroke holds a thought♪
♪획 하나하나에 생각이 담겨있습니다♪
♪Prosperity fades like dreams♪
♪번영은 꿈처럼 사라져 버립니다♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪과거 이야기가 내 영혼에 둥지를 틀고 있습니다♪